ABD ALRAHMAN ALHELANI

Senior Flutter Developer

+971 588-544-129 @ abood.helani@gmail.com

UAE, Dubai

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abd-airanman-



I am a software engineer who graduated from Arab international university (AIU), I worked in many IT companies for more than 5 years as a Flutter developer on many large-scale production projects using (Flutter, Dart, Android, and IOS), I got motivated by working in an organized environment.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Mobile App Developer

Global Hotel Alliance

- Build and enhance a loyalty system that linked with hotel reservation system, enhancing user engagement and retention.
- Implemented features such as point accumulation, redemption, and rewards tracking, utilizing technologies.
- Improved user experience by integrating search filters, reviews, and secure payment gateways into hotel reservation modules.
- Implemented Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) pipelines using Fastlane, automating the build, testing, and deployment processes for mobile applications.
- Advocated for and practiced Test-Driven Development (TDD) methodology, writing unit tests before implementing new features to ensure code quality, maintainability, and reliability.
- Actively participated in code reviews and pair programming sessions to promote best practices, identify potential issues early in the development cycle, and foster a culture of quality and collaboration.
- · Stacks: CI/CD, TDD, Flutter Appium Driver, Maestro, Oracle.

Team Lead of Mobile application developer

Silwana Infotech

- leading a team of 5 mobile developers coaching them, assigning tasks, and reviewing code.
- · make proper alignment between the product team and my team.
- · set features timelines and make sure the execution met the deadlines.
- · documenting the base architectures and design patterns in the app.
- · managing the releases of the apps and the hotfixes.
- · managing CI/CD in github actions using fastlane and bitrise.
- · monitoring the performance of our apps using firebase crashlytics .
- Stacks: Flutter, WebRTC, SIP, Smart contract, ClickUp, CI/CD.

Senior Mobile Application Developer

EJAF

= 2021 - 2022

Iraq (Remotely)

- building multivendor e-commerce applications that provide users the ability to pay for foods with delivery.
- testing the applications using integration test using applium flutter driver
- · applying real-time firebase database to track driver geometric.
- · applying filters for real-estate best matching.
- Stacks: Flutter, FCM, Google map API, social media authentication, PayTabs, Trello.

Senior Mobile Application Developer

Golden standard

UAE, Dubai (Remotely)

- building a shipping application that serves local orders, international orders, storage orders, and courier delivery.
- · integrating with google Maps APIs to track the driver in real-time and draw paths.
- · integrated sales reports and CRM system with DataOps solution, presenting.
- Stacks: Flutter, Google map API, Apple pay, Stripe payment gateway.

Mobile Application Developer

Octopus

= 2020 - 2020

Lebanon (Remotely)

- building an e-commerce application (cart, order, payment, chat contact ...etc).
- integrating with firebase and parse server to build real-time chat.
- · integrating with facebook graphQL to.
- Stacks: Flutter, Fcm, real-time chat(firebase, Parse server), Facebook graphQL.

STACK

Technical Skills

Firebase PGSQL Express ML

Management

MVC/MVP/MVVM

Click-Up & Jira Task Management

Test Driven Development (TDD)

Familiar

PHP	Laravel	Java	C#	C++	-
Python	MySQL	SQL	No.	de JS	_
Javascri	pt Swif	t Ob	Objective C		Matlab

AWARDS



CRYPTO EXPO BEST BIOCKCHAIN APP 2023 (UAE.DUBAI)

EDUCATION

Artificial Intelligence Engineering

الجامعة العربية الدولية Arab International University

2016 - 2020

 Software design and architecture, Machine Learning, Neural Network, Deep Learning, Image Processing, Multi-Media, Fuzzy logic, National Language Processing, Software design pattern, Object-oriented programming OOP), Unified modeling language (UML), Web service, Representational state transfer (REST), Compiler, Algo-rithm, Relational database, and Information retrieval subjects are all covered.

LANGUAGES

Arabic

English



Mobile Application Developer

Focus Code

- building an e-commerce application (cart, order, payment, chat contact ...).
- building a social media application (chat, post, comment, friend, follow, profile ...).
- building a religious application (prayer time, Prophet Mohammad speech, Evening remembrances, alarm ...).
- building a sport application that has statistics about football and oppor- tunity for user to suggest a plan for the game (statistics as tables and charts, player info, stadium info ...).
- integrating with firebase and parse server to build real-time chat.
- integrating with facebook graphQL to.
- Stacks: Flutter, Fcm, real-time chat(firebase, Parse server), Facebook graphQL.

Mobile Application Developer

CyberCell

苗 2019 - 2020 👂 Syria, Damascus

- building a restaurant reservation application (restaurant info, book reservation, rating pointing system ...).
- integrating with social media authentication.
- Stacks: Flutter, Fcm, Google map API, OAuth2.

PROJECTS

GHA DISCOVERY

Now, browse and book Member Rates of 10% or more off rooms at participating hotels worldwide. Explore Stay Offers, Experiences, Local Offers and Promotions available exclusively for members at 800+ hotels across 100 countries. Eligible purchases now earn you DISCOVERY Dollars (D\$), our generous rewards currency. You can spend your D\$ towards your total bill on your next visit.

(Google Play) (Apple Store)

Golex

Golex provides secure, trusted digital asset trading and asset management services, the highest quality investment opportunities, and the most rewarding trading experience.

(Google Play) (Apple Store)

izif - Learn Music Online

izif is the fast, fun way to learn, play and master the Guitar, Piano, Oud, and Violin. Our learning path, designed by expert music teachers, will help musicians of all levels improve, from complete beginners to professionals.

(Google Play) (APP Store)

الطريق الى الجنة

Welcome to the best comprehensive Islamic application without the Internet, "The Road to Heaven" is a wonderful application and deserves to try because it contains details and services of interest and benefit to every Muslim that makes him get closer to the Almighty.

(Google Play) (APP Store)